[ar:Lyrics artist]

[al:Album where the song is from]

[ti:Lyrics (song) title]

[au:Creator of the Songtext]
[length:How long the song is]
[by:Creator of the LRC file]

[offset:+/- Overall timestamp adjustment in milliseconds, + shifts time up, - shifts down]
 
[re:The player or editor that created the LRC file]

[ve:version of program]

[00:01.11]Lyrics line 1
[00:02.22][00:04.44]Lyrics line 2 & 4
[00:03.33] [00:05.55] Lyrics line 3 & 5 (with whitespace) 
[00:06.66]Lyrics line 6 [Lyrics in square brackets]
[99:99.99][00:07.77]Lyrics line 7
[00:08.88][Lyrics in square brackets] Lyrics line 8
[09:09.99] <09:10.99> Lyrics <09:11.99> line 9 <09:12.99> (with word time tags) <09:13.99> 

[1:1.1]Invalid time tag 1
[200:200.200]Invalid time tag 2
[33:99.33]Invalid time tag 3
[mm:ss.xx]Invalid time tag 4

Invalid lyrics line
